I think that we are in my friend Jordan
crane
what is it up it is so I'm happy to have
you here we haven't caught up for quite
a while but we just got like a quick
obviously you know what I have a ton
time we'll get a quick rundown of each
other's lives some crazy stuff has
happened to you and I mean I just want
to start it out with again saying I'm
glad you're here at the podcast but I'm
glad you're here with us to talk about
this and and you know what we're gonna
go into is is what you've been going
through as you know your your life
recently but at the same time you know
you're more than just that too so
there's other things that you want to
talk about and just hang out and dip
into I would love to talk about them so
Jordan cream you message me I had a
couple episodes of the podcast and you
kinda like know the positivity stuff
that I do you reached out to me a few
weeks ago and we had a couple
interactions back and forth you had
actually commented about in my first
description I mentioned the word c-diff
and it's funny because I was like oh
yeah it's just a little joke between
shading knife because she's a nurse and
so I hear about Thornton House about
c-diff and you're like well I actually
had it and it's a pretty serious thing
and I was like okay and then we talked
back and forth but so I just got the
lowdown if you don't mind giving the
listeners a little bit of lowdown what's
been like going on with you what's your
life okay so like well I'm gonna
celebrate nine months clean from alcohol
on the 18th which is in a couple days
which is great congratulations wonderful
Hugh I'm really close with my family
right now which is wonderful
um I just came from my mom's telling
about I remember her from high school so
cool your family would love to hear that
but um and you know I'm just really
trying to get back on track um I had a
rough patch this Edythe situation was
intense it's hilarious that it's a joke
because it honestly is so disgusting
but it is something that I went through
and it's something that I can talk about
because I'm actually really comfortable
with nurses now and doctors and my
family because my colon was talked about
for about four years
yeah it's all on the table at that point
yeah it really is there's if I had to
get a fecal transplant because of the
c-diff and my
and my dad say that I got it from Brown
University because he gets donated from
a college but it's so mean oh it's so
terrible like I just can't get away from
it but um I'm much better now like
everything's healed there is a chance I
could get it again but the doctors are
really careful if I get sick or
something they just get there really I
have to tell them what's going on and
they say okay we're just gonna go a
different round of antibiotics or
something that's easier to do on your
system because it just eats your stomach
like yeah I can imagine so so back up I
guess let's just for anybody who doesn't
know what is c-diff let's talk about the
realms around it and make sure we get a
good picture of what like it like we'll
talk about how you got it but what is it
um so it's basically when you can get it
from a couple different things but when
you contract it it's you are given
antibiotics and it takes out all the
good bacteria in your stomach and
replaces it with bad and so it's a
growth in your stomach basically that
it's an infection and it's really
painful for people our age but babies or
children and then older people can die
why is it more uncut why is it more
painful for our age I'm honestly not
sure like they I didn't care for that
part but um it was excruciating for me
like I couldn't move but I know that
it's not that painful for other people
so is it does it it's pain in your
stomach
obviously there's much other things
you're going through but like was so its
stomach related pains where you feel it
yeah like the first time I got it I was
in Mobile
like my stomach yeah it was just it
feels like your stomach is eating itself
it's burning and cramping and if you
can't alleviate it you know normally you
can I call go to the bathroom or I'll
stretch her maybe I'll fart or whatever
you know but also there's a complete
loss of blood you lose a lot of blood
that's how I knew I had it okay for
about a month I was just eating broth
like I was I couldn't eat food and I was
working a lot so I was just like I'm
just too busy to eat I want to drink
while I eat no so you were just kind of
pushing it to the side yeah yeah not a
big deal and then I went I was at
working I went to the bathroom and the
toilet was full blood powerful yeah and
so I freaked out I went to the doctor
and my stomach at that point was hurting
really badly and they did all these
tests like they could not figure out
what it was and then the doctor came he
touched the bed and I was like please
don't touch the
the bed oh geez and he's like you know I
think I know what this is like and he
did the seat of test and I had c-diff
like full-blown it was it had not been
caught for a while really bad okay so it
was from antibiotics is what what starts
it or is it I got it you can't get it
from anybody I did get it from
antibiotics but you can also get it from
feces so people go to the hospital and
they don't wash their hands that well so
it's contracted a lot at the hospitals
but it's also something that's going
around schools right now because they're
not using bleach anymore in the schools
they're using like you know easy for the
environment you know killing everything
yeah so people aren't watching their
hands well enough and they're getting it
from the faucets and stuff like that oh
well yeah so but I got it because I got
the birth control implant they put it on
my Harmon then it got infected and they
gave me antibiotics with penicillin in
them and I said I'm allergic to
penicillin they're like it only affects
one in like a hundred people I'm like
I'm always that person don't do it they
gave it to me oh no come back with an
allergic reaction they gave me another
round of antibiotics I guess you did
yeah
you poor thing that's so awful okay so
you had the I forget the name of it what
was the name the one that goes in your
arm is it oh oh yeah okay so so it goes
in there was it like weeks before you
started feeling no the minute they put
it in I said that it doesn't feel right
and they're like oh so your body's just
like no yeah and they were like oh no
it's fine it you know it's it's
something foreign and your arms gonna
feel like that and so they taped it up I
went to work and I just was like an
optometrist assistant I lifted a chair
to move it to the other side of the room
and it tore open and so it started
bleeding and I went in there like oh
yeah that's infected I was like didn't I
say hurt yeah it just went down that
path and now I mean in this this was
like years of so this was a whole
process of dealing with this because you
kept counting it - yeah so would you you
would get healed like you're feeling
better and then it would be it would
come back or do it takes a long time to
feel better like I soup and broth and
things that were easy for my stomach for
a really long time it's also super
contagious so I couldn't work so um
you're in the hospital a lot too because
I couldn't keep food down and I also was
drink
at the time so I was really sick a lot
and so they would keep me in the
hospital for a long time I always had to
be near toilet like and one that I could
use personally because it's really
contagious so you can imagine like
trying to improve your life and like
trying to just like live a regular life
without just you know like you can't
even have a whole sentence without
probably thinking about the sort of
stuff right at all times I can imagine I
mean cuz me I just know I've dealt with
like you know silly stomach pain
whatever or like eating bad food and not
admitting that it's a bad food or
whatever but man that sounds terrible so
the the drinking was it was it really
correlated with that or that's just like
that compounded you know honestly I
drank in high school and stuff too but
it really started bad I mean I wasn't
always I was never a good drinker I
would I got a DUI once when I was like
19 i I always broke something like a toe
or a concussion you know what I mean
like I was never the cool person but
still I started drinking everyday once I
had nothing to do every day like I was
sitting at horse you know and I was
miserable and I couldn't go out I
couldn't ski my friends most of them had
kids at that point I can't be around
babies I can't be around people so it
was just you got to do i sat at home and
drink all the time and and I just kind
of like I started nannying for my
parents actually for a minute when I
wasn't contagious because I wasn't like
I couldn't go straight back to work you
know and that was good for a while that
kind of started meeting getting out of
my shell but I don't know I just wasn't
happy and so I just kind of kept
drinking I tried a relationship for a
minute and that kind of blew up and that
was kind of when I I had my parents that
actually sat me down and said listen
this is not okay right about the
drinking yeah okay so at that point
pretty much everything was okay with my
seat if this was like 2016 and so I
think I was done with CF at that point
and I went into rehab so yeah okay and
so I mean you're doing better now but
you had some turmoil that happened in
between that you had mentioned before
like what so your parents did they they
gave you no tough love like we what was
that situation was that obviously a
difficult conversation that you guys had
to have no it's terrible you know and
they had to watch me just completely
like I wasn't even a person anymore
I mean hey it was so bad like I was just
sick all the time and I was up at weird
hours and I wasn't working I wasn't
doing anything after that relationship
ended there was a period where I didn't
really leave my room much like except
for to drink like it was just crazy and
there was a kid in the house it wasn't
cool like I was needing to do something
else they told me and I knew and so they
said several times they were gonna do it
and then finally they were like this is
crazy we're doing it so yeah that's a
terrible position for all of you to be
in and I feel terrible for what I put
them through like but I mean that's just
the start of it unfortunately that
wasn't the only thing that happened so I
went to the rehab at Kaiser in Clackamas
there's they have a little one in Kaiser
Permanente and I had my dad's insurance
then so and I thought this will be great
I'll figure it out I'll know how to
drink when I get out yeah figure out my
drinking yeah like I'll meet some people
along the way like it'll be alright and
I ended up like learning a little bit
and talking to other people who had
problems too and unfortunately I didn't
learn enough so but my parents on the
way out I was it was like a 21 days
thing and they I was like okay I'm ready
to come home and they're like whoa
you're not coming home like you are
gonna go to a program like there's
programs for people that can get out of
rehab and like it doesn't only take 21
days what did it wait so it there is so
when you're done with rehab you go is
that the typical is it 21 days for rehab
you know and 30 days is pretty typical
okay that was just a private insurance
thing now that was my only private
insurance the rest have been state and
they have all been like 30 days and a
lot of them are like six months to
Fiddler's three to six months if you're
going because of a court situation but I
went because I wanted to go so yeah so
the the right after so you do the the
rehab itself and then that transition in
between is there I'm just thinking for
anybody who is going through rehab if
they're willing to do that that's great
then that transition afterwards I never
thought about it but I imagine that's
predict is scary like you do it you're
like okay like I'm clean like I feel
like I can probably you know I've been
this many days we're getting some
momentum but
now you walk outside I feel like there
probably go what do I do now so well
unfortunately - if it's your first time
you see a lot it's like it's like a
crash course of people's lives you know
you hear from people who've been there a
lot and then you hear from people who
are just going there first time there
were a few of us a handful and I'm still
friends with them today which is cool we
don't talk a whole lot but it's like
high school you know but um the weird
thing for me was the first time I walked
out and I thought I thought about living
a different life but I don't know if I
was ready to do it and so my parents
told me I should go to a different
things so I had set up a thing at this
place called exchange Recovery and it's
in Vancouver and it's pretty great
program but it is something that
typically is like you want to stay for
like two years and you advance in the
program which is cool but your life is
pretty much recovery for that whole time
which is important for some people that
works um my friend Alyssa she does it
she graduated from that program she's
married she's doing great yeah sometimes
we need like a whole remapping if that's
why I need HEC yet right yeah and they
provide that and it's a church based
program so if you love that - it's all
great yeah I mean if you could add the
spirituality side of things that gives a
lot of beatin it's a lot of power in
that yeah so I went there and I actually
almost had six months and I was just not
happy I was really starting to boil down
the program is Christian based so they
don't run I'm a everybody should have
the same rules all the time kind of
person and if they're variated
or if they're if they're changed for
other people it makes sense because of
recovery but I didn't understand it at
that point so I was like why isn't this
being run this way you know what I mean
and they kept saying you know this is
gonna take you out like you need to
focus on yourself in your recovery and
it took me out so yeah so I ended up
going to a different recovery house they
have one that they have them all over
Vancouver they're great everywhere
honestly
Spokane's hot spot it's nuts but um I
went there I lasted like three months
and I relapsed again but they gave me a
second chance and I used it to continue
working where I was working and I was at
Buffalo Wild Wings then and then
somebody at the house asked if I wanted
to get my own apartment and I was like
that sounds kind of tight you know there
were there are so many restrictions in
those kind of houses and
it's a group living situation which
comes with its own stressors and yeah
but you're just never alone you know and
which is good though you know what I
mean if you think about it you need that
a little bit like there are different
ways that it can work for everyone but
it's structure that's important in the
beginning I think that for a ton of
people yeah but there are just struggles
so it's not all fun and games you know
but I decided to go out on with this
other person and I didn't know that the
house I was living in was also for
veterans and so they didn't need to be
sober to live there so when I got there
I knew she had smoked a bit but when I
got to the apartment she started
drinking a lot too and it was probably
that point that I was like you know I'm
on my own I'm doing great I'd been
working about Flo Wild Wings for almost
a year I was making my own money I had
my own apartment
maybe I kicked this you know maybe I'm
doing okay so I started to drink too
I couldn't handle living with her she
moved out in a very ugly situation and I
just didn't know what to do
I was really unhappy I was drinking all
the time at that point I think I had
been fired from Buffalo Wild Wings I
started working in it this place called
Elmer's did you feel that you had like
quote-unquote relapsed or did you feel
that you had like I had taken my life in
a different direction I decided that I
wasn't gonna live sober but I could
handle it if you felt in control of some
sorts or yeah okay
but uh honestly my life was so out of
control um to backtrack a little bit of
where my headspace was at that point in
high school I my first experience with
any sexual form was rape and I was 15
and so it was just nuts like I got
through it and then I was raped again in
college I have had boyfriends throughout
that time and I've kind of talked to a
couple people about it like my mom for
sure but not really the help I needed to
get right so um I've had boyfriends also
like serious and not and in my
experience it's all been like sex is
meant not for you like it's meant for
other people like it's something taken
from you yeah they're feeling their need
you're part of that yeah yeah it's just
not the way it should be right so I'm
now super unhealthy my
body it doesn't feel like a body anymore
because of the c-diff right I have been
examined by so many doctors so many
people know about my insides
oh yeah like it was just that you
wouldn't really think about actually as
like I just feel like you know everybody
knows about all of me and it's it's a
huge vulnerability yes right and at this
point I was only working I wasn't really
seeing my family because they had all
expressed concerns and I was like done I
was just unhappy I'm gonna live this way
I just need to figure out like what my
next move is so I found out a friend I
had a lot of friends that I thought were
friends and they actually were just
taking advantage of me but um she
suggested this sex-trafficking form of
work and I was like I don't know but
coming from my standpoint not feeling
like a human sex is something to be
taken it seems such like a crazy idea
that kind of felt like maybe I'm gonna
get like maybe this is where my part
comes in you know maybe I get something
for this finally you know what I mean
like yeah maybe though right
it was horrible yeah so but I did it and
I thought it was okay and then I started
like getting really sick one time I went
to the doctors and they tested my body
for different alcohol and drugs and
stuff and there were drugs in my body
that I didn't take and I was waking up
and the door was unlocked and nobody was
there
and it was really unsafe and I was just
scared all the time I didn't sleep at
night because people knew where I lived
it was really scary not comfortable of
course it doesn't feel like home I don't
have all these all these physical issues
going on I think you're getting it
together of course yeah so was you know
so you're going through it you know this
this crazy just sex trafficking stuff
you're you're still drinking was was
this around like a rock bottom for you
you would think it would be right so
okay I am I'm going to the hospital at
this point like once a week in the ER
which is causing a problem for what I do
because you can't just disappear so and
even if you're in the hospital it's not
safe right so
and I my parents came and they were
getting kind of weirded out like I
wasn't answering the door when they came
over I didn't want them to come over
like there were just a lot of signs red
flags right so um when they did come
over if I did answer the door I was like
completely incoherent one time they came
over and I wasn't coherent and they for
some reason they took my phone I don't
know if it was ringing I don't know what
was going on but this was one of the
times I was taken to the hospital that
there were a lot of drugs in my system
that I didn't take and she was out of it
right and so pretty much they they took
my phone and they saw what I had been
doing like all the texts the things that
had been said the people that were
involved and they called the friend I
had a friend that told me about it right
and I would just say why I was making
money or whatever why I had money in my
account why I was okay without a job
stuff like that that I was working for
her sister who worked in Mexico and she
was making us purses and stuff and we
were selling him here right and it
wasn't a legit story but it some
elaborate thing that yeah yeah and so
they called her and she sold me out
completely right she's like no this is
really unsafe she never made a purse
ever Yeah right yeah she's like I'm not
even her friend really like yeah I was
actually really bad yeah that blew up in
my face right so at this point now my
parents know all the things that you
would wish that they would never know
right my dad could like hardly look at
me it was like the most painful
experience in my life I think and and
it's just a lot because nobody knows
what you're thinking right in that space
obviously a person who's healthy and
happy wouldn't make those decisions and
put themselves in dangerous positions
all it like the life-threatening
everyday like that's what I was doing I
was just like let's die I don't care I'm
thinking that you need to do it or you
deserve to do it or there's never gonna
be anything better like I had dreams of
like being married before and like
having a family and working in normal
job you know I would have never
anticipated I didn't know any of these
things happen I would have never I mean
again not that you just oh this person
is gonna have this thing happen to them
and it's like of course not but jeez I
mean I was totally shocking to hear yeah
so your parents come over they looked at
do they what what happened after that
they uh they took me to the hospital
before I went to the hospital one of the
two they might know yeah that yeah the
drugs room system right I woke up and
they weren't there and my phone was gone
and I panicked cuz I remembered them
being there a little bit but I couldn't
remember where my phone was and I
emailed my mom she's like I have it and
then I knew everything was bad so they
came over again and said you know you
need to go to rehab and the hospital and
I think I'm pretty sure that's how it
went down I was a little out of it but I
went to the hospital they found the
drugs and everything and I'm pretty sure
that's about the time that they sent me
away right or no that's when I decided
that I was just gonna die like I was
just giving up he's done trying the
hospital said if I kept drinking I was
gonna die so I did I just had drinking
right and I also just thought you know
if I could just make another month's
rent probably I will die so I did what I
did like as much as I could I called
everybody I knew like it was horrible
and I didn't I
at the end of it I knew I needed to go
somewhere like I couldn't do this
anymore my body was so sick I tried to
get a job at this fish place cuz I was
like I need to make money right away and
it was like a McGrath fish house and I
got hired I worked there 45 minutes it
was the day after I got out of the ICU I
said an ICU for eight days the hospital
for four right not in any position to go
to work the next day pickin up right
like valium for eight days sedated you
can't think and I lasted 45 minutes and
they were like are you okay like can you
I feel like you're not understanding it
was like I'm not like I just got out of
the hospital and I can't work and so
they sent me home and I'd called my
parents and I said I'm yeah I mean being
in that position Jordan I can't imagine
like the like okay I'm doing the thing
you know I'm getting my life better but
here I am I can't even pay attention you
know I you know that's that's got to be
terrible to in my memory it was pretty
much gone like mixed with alcohol and
all value it just took time again well
there's a lot of things that are going
on your life that it's like I don't even
want to think about those memories you
know who wants to think about my memory
but it's not too great lately no yeah it
was just awful and so I went to rehab I
thought I did really good and I got out
and
I had bills like the next day like it
was I I was not ready for what happened
I went to a clean and sober house I
think that time or maybe I was at my
parents
but regardless next Danny other
different bills so what did I do I knew
how to make money so I went and made
money and there was alcohol there and it
relapsed the next day okay so there were
a couple of times that something like
this happened and one of the times I
ended up in a motel for like four days
like really sick I was in the ER twice
during that time like super dangerous my
parents don't even know where I was they
were about to file a missing-persons
report they thought I was dead like
because I drank so much they thought I
went and crashed my car died in the car
cuz I threw up or something you know
what I mean oh yeah in anything could
happen at that point when they don't
know oh they were so upset one time I
was gone and the cops came to my mom's
house because I had hit something with
my car and I had kept going and people
saw and they called the cops
and so the cops came to my mom's house
cuz that's what the address said and it
was they couldn't find me and I wanted
in order to send them and so literally
like my mom was like oh my gosh she
crashed her car where is she why can't
we find her yeah oh my gosh okay so
you're you're having this just like
you're constantly like going back and
just not not but what changed like what
yeah I mean you seem you seem so normal
now you have a great conversation with
me your eyes are bright you seem healthy
you look good like what's what what
changed here what was this like flip so
I unfortunately took me a few times
right I had to go to rehab like I want
to say five times but this last time I
had to go to Spokane and while I went to
Spokane a lot they sent me far away from
my family because the more my family
visited me the more irritated I got
because it was just really hard they
were really upset there were feelings
you know they knew what had happened I
had guilty yeah I thought that made you
feel a lot of shame you know just by
them being around just obviously in
everybody would write so the person I
worked with just kept sending me farther
away so I wouldn't have visitors and I
went to this place I had about a hundred
girls in it and they some of them most
of them had come from a situation where
it was either jail or drug correction
you know
so it's kind of hardcore honestly for me
I was a little bit like but the more you
go to rehab like it's kind of intense
it's not your average day it's a lot of
intense conversations you hear about
stuff like this every day
like I'm not the only person who's gone
through this it's not weird at all it's
something that is so common
unfortunately for people in my situation
or for people just with mental illnesses
like or for people that have just been
raped and set up to have a hard life
like it's just you know or medical
situations there's just so many factors
that can hit in home for people and so
um I went to that rehab there were about
a hundred girls I was cutting at this
point really bad okay it was just
something that knew that you had started
doing already knew yeah I don't even
doing it for like a month
Jesus so crazy like you're just you know
the opposite of getting better you're
just thinking that you need to be more
in pain I know
terrible that you were feeling like that
yeah and so um the problem is if you cut
at rehab it's not funny but I've been
there a long time and I'm done now so it
is funny and for people that have been
there it's a little funny but you can't
use your razor if they if you cut they
take it of course go a month without
shaving it sucks
so how never mustache or what know that
your legs okay I'm human and you warm
so I just I learned my lesson like don't
do it there but the problem was also at
this one that they were too big to
handle a situation like that and they
weren't focused so much on mental health
like they were it was a behavioral
health place but not this yeah there's a
lot of problems with it with a hundred
people right so um they kept sending me
to the hospital I went to the hospital
four times in two weeks and each time
they'd be like you're at a behavioral
place go back so they'd send me back so
I'm at this place with a hundred women
you'd think we're better with age we're
not in a situation like that it was like
a high school with women who should know
better and everybody's got a mental
illness or a drug problem and a drug
problem
like it was rough and they called me a
psycho there were about me cutting
people's like ask to help but they
didn't help like you wouldn't think
there'd be a bunch of judgment in a
place like that it was really rough and
so I kind of blew up one night and and I
called my parents and I said I'm leaving
and they were like what and I was like I
cannot be here it's not good for my
mental health I'm gonna kill myself like
at that point there was a closet
at the end of the hall that they left
unlocked sometimes and I knew there was
bleach inside of it and I was literally
I mean think about that sentence right
there like you know a lot of people like
oh you I can't imagine how that would
feel that's how it feels you having
those thoughts I there's some bleach in
that closet that's what you're thinking
that's what and I didn't get it out of
my head you don't want to be doing that
you know and one of the times I went to
the hospital I told the EMT that and he
said honestly that's one of the most
painful ways not to die and I still
couldn't get it out of my head like it
was just the only thing I could think of
it was college cause as much damage as
possible like maybe I wouldn't wake up
this time because after that ICU I just
I thought I was dying when I was in the
ICU because you're so out of it like
when I woke up and was alive I was so
upset
like II imagine being that like right
upset that you're alive and your parents
are crying and they're all sad and
you're just I can't believe I'm alive
right now like yeah you're still
inconvenience by this life yes and so I
did leave and I went straight to a motel
motel 6 is kind of where I go and you
can always find easy people out of motel
6 and I don't don't go there honestly
but so you'll know why in a minute so um
I went to motel 6 I drank a bunch and I
called my counselor not my counselor
she's like a she helps people get find
places to go to rehab and I called her
and my case manager and I was like this
is what happened this is my mat she's
like I know your mom's called me several
times and we were wondering where you
were and I'm gonna send you a cab in the
morning and you're gonna go to back here
and we're gonna send you somewhere else
and I was like okay um there was another
place that was connected to that
behavioral place that's called Koza
and they had a waiting list it's a
smaller program for people with really
bad mental health and so I was actually
on that list but it wasn't happening
soon enough so I left and the cab came
and I went to the bus stop and there was
a store across from the bus stop so I
picked up like four things a little wine
boxes and I drank the whole bus ride and
I don't know what happened I woke up in
Seattle I was supposed to be in
Vancouver
I will come Seattle at 12:00 am in a
hospital
jeez I don't know where I don't know
what happened I don't know if I shuffle
in the wrong way
yeah I don't know if they called the car
like the police cuz I was on the bus and
I was drunk I I literally don't know how
or maybe you just like thought you're
genius and hopped on another bus after a
couple hours well it was on the way it's
a stop but it doesn't make sense that I
oh you're going North Vancouver Canada
from Spokane to Vancouver from sawaki
yeah anyway so um I don't have a phone
because I've been in rehab so much I
don't have a phone so I do now but I
didn't then anyway um it uh it's 12 a.m.
right what am I going to do doctor just
gave me benzos we already know I don't
do well with those and alcohol so
instead of like they wake me up and
they're like you're gonna or you need to
go and I'm like what where am I like
they're like you're in Seattle it's
about 12 a.m. here's your stuff I only
brought like one bag in a blanket
I had like suitcases I don't know where
they were at that point I'm like and so
um I leave I don't know what to do I
don't have a phone it's 12 a.m.
everybody I know thinks I was supposed
to be in Vancouver I'm sure they're
freaking out but at this point I'm
really just thinking like what am I
gonna do right now so I go and see a
bench in the hospital I sit down on it
and I went to lay down in this guy oh
the security guard was like you can't
stay here so I'm like okay so I go
outside it's freezing right because this
is February of this year and I'm okay so
I I kind of go to like a bar but I don't
have any money so I'm like trying to
figure out like are there people around
like what am I gonna do and so I did
have a little money so I went and got
some alcohol of course because what else
am I gonna do so and I kind of like laid
down in like a little window area nook
of a building and more cops came by
can't lay here I'm like yeah that makes
sense I guess but so I hate you can't
see really anywhere no so I I walked I
just kind of kept walking and at this
point I'm kind of more drinking more I'm
really out of it the benzos are not good
I'm tired I'm just like this is like
three o'clock in morning this point oh
yeah whatever
oh yeah and I get pulled inside of a
homeless man's tent and I think you can
imagine what happens you know I didn't
know what to do I had no phone and it
was freezing I had nowhere else to go
I literally stayed with him until the
morning because what if I left and
something else happened to Mike it's a
terrible thing to have to be afraid of
oh my gosh
it was horrible he was like smoking meth
the whole time there was it was danger
he was so psychotic like he was like
yelling at me in the morning as soon as
I could have got up and he was like
where are we going like this guy thought
we were gonna hang out yeah their life
now we're best friends right and then I
was kind of in my mind are you thinking
like thinking at this point is this my
life now I'm like I don't know like what
people don't even know where I am like
so I told them like I need to go call my
mom and see if she can put some money
because I had my card like in my account
or something and I can get somewhere and
I go across the street there's a bus
stop and I use this strangers phone and
I called my mom and she was so worried
and she put some money in my account so
we get on a bus to look for a motel and
he's just like scaring me right you're
still hanging out there yeah do you want
to hang out with the guy who just like
rape you yeah like so but I didn't know
what to do like he was dangerous the cow
and so he wanted to sit behind me on the
bus and so I saw him Motel I told him
I'm getting off and he said like I
thought you're not gonna want to go to
that Motel it's too expensive and I was
like I'm getting off so I got off and he
didn't get off and so I called the cab
as soon as I got to the hotel and I got
as far away as I could like yeah because
I didn't know what else to do and I
didn't want him to come back and so I
ended up at this motel 6 4 and that's
where I go and the I'm outside I have a
weed map and I gotta be honest this
whole time I'm praying right cuz at this
point I'm kind of like okay God tell me
like is this gonna be my life like am i
you have I made so many mistakes that
this is it right um but can I ever go
home like how do I talk to my parents
about this like how do I tell them where
I'm at like I don't even know how to
explain it you know my my own
own brother like um I had my okay so you
know what let's keep moving real quick
I'll go back so I go to this motel 6 um
and this person is outside watching me
use this weed map and I'm like talking
to them about the weed map and they're
like we actually have weed like do you
want to just come to my motel room and
I'm like tie it like saves me a cab ride
right money I don't have and we don't
probably cheaper from these creepy
people send Motel 6 so they don't call I
go get it and come back I think it's
over I think they're weird that they
don't want to talk to me they come to my
room at 5 a.m. and push their way in and
they held me hostage with them for two
days while they use my debit cards to
cash fake checks oh yeah it was two
women and a man and when the women and
the man weren't there or the man was
always there but when the woman was gone
like the other woman would stay and they
were like smoking heroin and like it was
so crazy that there's people that are
just living this whole different reality
oh just like he just got pulled right
into it and felt that you needed to be
there like that you deserve to be there
so I'm like I couldn't leave like the
girl one of the one of the girls was
younger and she was probably my age and
she was just like she gets really mean
like she was doing heroin and meth and
she's like she's gonna freak out and she
will beat you up like she's this isn't
gonna go well for you yeah she's like
you need to get out of here and I was
like I can't leave like every time I
went to leave she would come and say
like you're not leaving I'm not done
that check needs to clear cuz she cashed
a check and it hadn't cleared right yeah
this is hot this is a hostage that using
your money like this is crazy so I I
just gonna leave like okay so the girl
leaves and then another person comes and
she's it's like the middle of the night
and she's like screaming and she is on
meth and she's like telling me that I
don't respect the woman but took me like
I'm not giving her enough respect and
she's got a gun outside and she was
gonna kill me like she's like this is
ridiculous and I don't know what
happened exactly right there but then
she went to make a phone call to call
the police because she got this feeling
that her mom was in trouble so she
wanted the police to drive by her house
right so they didn't that girl that have
been keeping me hostage
here's that she's on the phone with the
cops and freaks out on her so she leaves
oh so I'm thinking at least I'm not
gonna get shot tonight right and then
the next day the check doesn't clear
I pray literally like God if I was meant
to leave get me out of here I don't know
how I'm gonna leave other than that and
I tell her the check did not clear I'm
leaving and she goes you need to wait
and I was like no I'm not waiting like
I'm leaving and I opened the door and I
walk out and I have a cab waiting and
she literally was like call me tomorrow
and I was like what like she let me
leave the man was there to call me
tomorrow I called the cops as soon as I
left I told them everything that
happened I told him what room they were
in and they never went and found those
people I'm not [__] you I also
called about the guy in downtown Seattle
but do you think it's because they just
see you as I go you you were a part of
it like you're just I don't know what
they saw but it was so unfortunate those
people like cash fake checks like they
had people's mail they had bags of mail
I mean they're they're holding someone
hostage because heroin and meth like
what more emotive do you need to go
there and they never went jeez yeah so
um okay so so keep going with that you
got out of there though I got out and I
I ended up I think I came home two of
these stories might mix a little Mike my
memory is still kind of weird you know
you know I just had a podcast where I
talked about my childhood before you
came over a couple hours ago and I'd
talk with Shaylee and I said the same
thing and I was like I'm not sure
exactly if I'm like mixing is up you
know cuz a memory with a lot of
traumatic things are it's messed up and
right and it you know well thank you for
keeping going yeah I appreciate this but
so so one of the times I went back I
couldn't go home I just I had decided I
can't go home I called another friend of
mine right I don't have any good friends
at this point so I call him and I say
this is what I used to do so I used to
work with like is dangerous it's not
good but I think we can do it together I
go out with them I wake up four days
later in a motel room with people
I don't know my car is outside I don't
have the keys I don't know what happened
i straight-up don't know
in four days like I don't know if
there's some video of me somewhere I
don't know who was with me I don't know
what I did I don't I don't know if I was
awake that's a long time four days
yes or not no yeah and when I woke up I
had a legit like stand over you watch
what you do you're not going in there
without me pimp it was horrible what and
I'm a crazy position to be in
I didn't know what to do you just wake
up like that I didn't I don't know what
did I get myself into
yeah not even yourself at that point
right and I still don't know what
happened that person really won't talk
to me but I kind of texted him one time
on Instagram like dude what happened
like he was super mad at me so I don't
know if I like went out took a drink of
something and got my stuff and was like
go home or so I don't know what happened
yeah I couldn't you could have just like
peace Alan Amy might not even know he
might like you just left that's all I
know right I don't know what he knows
but I know he didn't know actually it's
so crazy that you have to you know feel
like you know you you have to put
together what happened in your life
that's awful and this guy has my phone
right and he's starting to make like
some kind of website and we're in a
motel 6 believe it and they're all doing
meth and I still haven't done meth or
heroin which is shocking right but I
just didn't hit that low honestly every
time I was in this position I was really
sick because I'm an alcoholic at that
point right really bad and I need
alcohol like I can't just not drink or
eat and I wasn't like they weren't
feeding me or giving me how qahal right
they were just you know he was rolling
violently from oh it's horror I was so
sick and they kept trying to move us
because you know you can't be operating
something like that in a place for him
very long like motel people know what's
going on and so um my back started to
hurt really bad like a couple days later
I needed like constant ice or cold water
on it like it was really hurting and I
was really throwing up like I could
hardly do what they kept asking me to do
and so um he went to go get food or
something and I wasn't alone but he came
back and I couldn't eat any of the food
and he's like I don't know what to do
for you and he's like I'm kind of
worried like that you aren't okay and I
was like I'm not like and at this point
he saw at my car right and like
computer and all my stuff so I was like
he needs here's what do you do when
you're like this and I said I need to go
to hospital so he took me to the
hospital and dropped me off he took my
car and my phone and my computer and my
parents don't know where I'm at and
apparently they got like text during
this time but I didn't text them I
didn't have my phone so I don't know
what happened but they were just like
keeping up some story or something maybe
oh yeah and so my dad I think I called
him or something from the hospital
because I was there for like two or
three days and they my kidneys were
failing by the way so that was and
that's the pain in your back that's what
that was from yeah can you failure and
so they kept me to fix it and when I
called the guy to come pick me up he
okay so it was the day I was getting out
here call the guy to pick me up my dad
shows up and I'm like dad you need to
leave and you can do that in hospitals
like you can say they can't see me and
so I was about to say that and then my
dad's like we can't hold your phone
you'll never find that person again and
at this point I'm like I hadn't heard
them I was I was worried I was like
overcome with fear these people have my
phone my car and my computer like
everybody is everybody I know pictures
where I live who my parents are I was
just like you don't know what you just
did you don't just disconnect somebody
from a situation like that it's
dangerous like what if they had tried to
find me and they had my car insurance
like in the car you know what I mean we
have a million different ways of getting
to you everything and so I freaked out
and it's so bad that my dad dropped me
back off in a motel 6 and I waited just
to see if they would come back to find
me and they didn't come back and so I
tried to kill myself there in the motel
6 that night because the doctor at the
hospital gave me benzos and I knew I
could over like drink too much and so I
drank a ton and then I actually tried to
like burn myself with a coat hanger cuz
I thought I could like get through the
skin and I'd bleed out like it was I was
just done right nothing right and so my
parents got me back and then I went back
to this rehab right well before that I
had to stay at my dad's for a minute and
because it's not just easy you can't
just like be like I'm sick and need to
go to rehab there's like what
eating lists and stuff yeah there's so
many yeah and insurance and stuff so I
had to wait with my dad for a while and
I like one point I was alone with my
brother and he was like he said
something about my phone or something
and I was like yeah I don't have it
anymore he's like yeah that's right pimp
has it like hmm like but you don't feel
like it's gonna get better right like at
that point like your family knows you're
not a person like what the things you
had to do that you like beyond your
control you know yeah you've had to
completely strip yourself down to
something that's not you but it's hardly
even a person you know you just you just
out outwardly living out pain you know I
can't imagine so your brother like you
and your brother have always been pretty
close okay and he's my only like blood
relation but you seem like you were able
to have good conversation I guess that's
right what I knew from back in the day
yeah like I don't think I think he there
were a lot of mistakes I made in college
just like partying and doing silly
things not anything like this right that
he was like I wish he would make better
choices but I think that when this
happened it kind of made him just feel
like who is this person you know I don't
know how I feel I can't speak for him
but I'm sure I feel like from my point
of view I can understand why he might
say I don't even want to be a part of my
life anymore you know what I mean and
like I didn't go to his wedding this
year I was out of rehab I had six months
clean I could have gone Mikey uninvited
me so I'm sorry um it was just like
honestly toughest thing I think I've
experienced so far which is crazy right
so let's just say where I'm at now so I
went after all this I go to the hospital
and because I couldn't I couldn't get
back I kept drinking I couldn't get back
and I called the cops right so I'm in
the cab I tell my mom what's going on
she calls me Michaela my case manager
she calls a rehab I get there to detox
they don't have my phone number and my
information I don't know what happened
but it didn't work I couldn't go there
so my options were to go to the hospital
and say I will kill myself if I leave
and they admit you into the like the
mental health ward and so then based on
that they kept me for ten days in the
mental health ward
then through those ten days Michaela got
me into cosa and so I ended up
I rehab again at the one that I could
have gone to if I'd waited on the
waiting list and not left that other
rehab
Oh way back when yeah well actually that
was just March this March
okay so that the February I left that
place I was only out for like two weeks
during that whole okay and then Koza is
that the name you said what is how do
you spell that
okay in it was that that was good for
you that was you know obviously the best
experience my life it was awesome it was
a smaller version of the other place so
there are people that didn't want to be
there sure but certs rehab you don't go
cuz you want to go um but it was great
like they had a mental health counselor
there that was fantastic and he talked
to me about how how my parents would
feel if I died but more importantly just
like how I could live like it's and how
thoughts are just thoughts you know
everything's just thought until you make
it in action like anymore
yeah and people have thoughts like it's
okay to have them but you know like let
them the hell out yeah yeah don't keep
them in there yeah
don't feel terrible don't beat yourself
up for having them or thinking like well
I guess I deserve this like that's like
you know I guess I have to live with
that homeless guy now or whatever you
know yeah thoughts you don't those
aren't you yeah and like how you can
better your life and like it just like
it changed my thinking I heard a lot of
things there that I really liked and
they taught us a lot about drinking and
about how to like talk to people like
cuz it's really hard you know I've been
in rehab now on and off for a year I've
been in on and off in recovery for it
since 2016 once you go through something
so dehumanizing it's weird that I work
at an IHOP right now and go to church on
Sundays and live a normal life like it's
hard to go from that to that like
sometimes I'll get really frustrated at
work because somebody's upset that I got
their order wrong or that the cooks
messed up because I was homeless last
week you know what I mean not last week
but like yeah like this is not a big
deal no yeah so like it's hard to make
the like conversion back to it reality
like cuz your reality was so deformed
and so like I had a conversation with my
friend Alyssa about today
how did you do this like did you get
frustrated with people because it's not
their fault that they didn't have to go
through that thank God they didn't have
to go through that but it's hard I mean
but you went through that and then now
you're here like I mean you're here like
telling the whole story like being brave
and so that definitely gives a ton of
people I'm sure you've already given a
lot of people a lot of strength just by
telling it so thanks for that but but
it's crazy because it makes me think you
know like you're the worker dye have
like we don't think about that like
we're just at IHOP and we're just like
and I'm so bummed about my pancakes
being wrong or whatever and it's like
that person like that person just went
through the most crazy last five six
years of her life you know it changes
our interactions when we're interacting
from from day to day so so what would
you say since you you know you have been
to more than one rehab what would you
say was like different about this one
like what you know obviously there's a
few things that were profound like oh
those are just thoughts you know that
was probably a huge thing just like I
don't have to follow those those honor
me but like what was different about
this rehab center um not all of them are
co-occurring like mental health and
alcohol or or drag yeah any drug but
some of them are just geared toward
recovery like for our for drug and
alcohol like I had mental health
problems I don't honestly believe I have
him anymore
I was literally like healed I don't have
the same thoughts I had anymore I don't
I mean I'm a normal person I have using
dreams sometimes and they freak me out I
wake up and I'm like but like I prayed
I've gone to church my parents and
praying for me forever
um I think God finally just answered a
prayer like he I don't feel when I got
out of rehabs before I was always like
kind of bummed to be around people who
drank like I couldn't I don't know I
just couldn't be around it now I mean
I'm fine with it like if you need to
drink that's fine but I just don't and I
don't feel like yeah like you're you're
actually in control yeah like I'm in
control until I get in front of it you
know yeah sure that's probably a
difficult thing too
it used to be yeah and I'm sure it is
for a lot of people like it's really
uncomfortable I don't think people think
about that like um because people don't
they shouldn't have to change her my
wife for you but I think
people should like consider that you're
really struggling like I always think
about like Twilight honestly like cuz
when you bit like for the first time it
feels like beer on humans feels like
fire in your throat it's a little
factoid that an ounce I want people
think about that like you're putting the
alcoholic or the drug addict through
that when you bring that it makes me
that uncomfortable it used to right now
I don't care like I'm just kind of get
frustrated like when people abused it
you know I'm like I just wish he knew
hot and healthy it was but well that's
just because you care in your life I
know how bad this could be right that's
all like but it's just it's just
different now I love being around my
family I have a nine year old sister
she's freaking the bee's knees and I'm
just kind of renewing relationships I
didn't make it to my brother's wedding
technically I wasn't invited but we're
gonna skip past that because we've seen
each other twice since then and it's
been wonderful and I felt good to hear
yeah you know what Jordan you have a
whole whole rest of your eyes is life oh
yeah experience good times together yeah
you know when I can see where he's
coming from you know I I think that it's
important to know where somebody's head
spaces before they make those choices I
think if I could talk to him I would
probably just like real honest one time
maybe I will but I think I would just
probably like say you don't know where
you know I didn't just go out and say I
want to do this like I want this life
like help me be horrible you know like
help me be miserable but I did you know
I found it unfortunately and you know I
wouldn't I wouldn't try to embarrass
anyone but that's not where I was that's
not even what I was thinking and I'm
sorry if it looks yucky but it just
happened like and it was dangerous and
it's something that can happen to a lot
of people like well that's something
that you clearly see like that you
reached out to me like you're willing to
talk about this and be so honest about
it I mean that's just that typical you
know we always hear like you don't think
it's gonna happen to you like that you
know Jordan I new year like I feel I
didn't know about any of this stuff
I don't know that any of it happened and
now but it is cool I you know something
I was thinking bout as you're explaining
this to me you're telling me about this
like this girl who's in a hotel room and
you're doing these things and I'm just
like what you're just like this
smart well-spoken person to me the door
that I know so it's it's cool too
you know there's I'm sure there's a lot
of parts of you that you had to like
refined and there's new parts of you
that you discovered but I mean it's it's
I hope it gives somebody a little faith
of like you know if they're if they're
listen to my podcast in that hotel room
right now like you have to you you gonna
be normal again one day you don't have
to be in that situation like I mean and
it's not your fault that's the most
important part like because I was just
like no this is just the way in my life
is going and I think that it's important
to say that I had a friend who had a
worse situation than mine like she had a
really hard life name was Meagan Mayer
and I met her in treatment and she
passed away a couple months ago from a
overdose because that fentanyl was like
crazy up in heroin right now and she had
eight months clean that she was doing
great but it was just a bummer so she
had she wanted help like and she
couldn't cuz she can't now and so I just
thought that was kind of my point where
I thought I need to talk about this and
then all of a sudden you were like
c-diff and I was like I know that way I
know that's like so like the fact that
it you know in what's funny is you
messaged me and I was like listening
back as like I don't think I actually
can sometimes I'll edit out like if I
get rambling for too long oh yeah but I
think I ended it out even the joke that
we had about literally cuz I listened
the whole podcast I was like I want to
hear what he says about it but you know
what's cool is I don't know I just like
the fact that it led to you messaging me
and now you're here and you know there's
this minute like how I mean there's a
lot of women who are gonna have a lot of
strength from this one like there was a
point where you were like if you wanna
come on my podcast let me know and I was
thinking like nah I don't have anything
to say crazy idea I need to say anything
and then I thought no I kind of do need
to say something because like I don't
know I honestly there's a person I know
that's kind of starting to seem like
going through something I went through
like where I was working but I my life
was just kind of interim I was calling
in a lot and I was sick and it was
starting to show at work and I kind of I
feel like I need to talk to that person
to you know like I just feel like I
don't want to be overbearing but like if
I get help somebody or just say listen I
have been there and if you don't want to
do what I did like there are other
choices right exactly tries to get help
and no you deserve hell
anyways ways to get it I think just I
always like to create this you know like
with this podcast especially but even
just like our friend group is just like
changing like my personal close friends
where we're starting to get to the point
where we're having these open
conversations that are like instead of
when that person's not around like yeah
so I'm so is drinking we're all
uncomfortable it's like like hey like
you love that person and it's gonna be
hard but maybe have a little bit of a
conversation can surround it maybe ask
him a couple questions we're starting to
all trying to like make it to where it's
okay to talk about these things like
it's okay to go to your friends it's
okay like you don't have to like you
know no I think it should be talked
about I think that honestly this whole I
mean my mom was even like are you sure
you want to share details like what if
you what about the backlash you know and
I honestly just asked like a couple of
my close people like it wasn't gonna
embarrass you in any way and they said
no and I said okay then I'm gonna do it
like um I just feel like it needs to be
talked about because like when I first
started doing this like when that friend
told me about the service she used there
are people in this town who use that
service to call people to call me you
know what I mean like I know people so
like it this is a thing that needs to be
talked about in our town because there
are people using that service so I'm
sure there are people like me I just
work on it I just don't think that the
personal you know like it like you were
obviously going through some pain but I
just think that if you're in a position
to be using that you probably if you
don't think you're going through pain
but you're using a service like that I
feel like you prop there may be some
things that that need to be dealt with
your life right I think I would say what
one thing I do want to talk about so
something that I have noticed like our
age group so you probably noticed even
outside of the situation so religion
when it comes to like spirituality
religion
everyone's so uncomfortable about it
like I I have a friend who who he's like
a wonderful human being like I love
talking to him I like you know he's very
interesting intelligent and we were
talking we're going on about like music
production or some probably some science
or something cool and then you started
talking about religion and he was like
yeah I remember his voice got quiet he
goes well so I'm Christian yeah and I
remember like just thinking like dude
you shouldn't be ashamed of that
you know but but it's our society it's
just super weird you know like we feel
uncomfortable talking about things so
what what I would love to hear from you
Jordan is is you mentioned religion you
said it plays an important role in your
life now what what has it given you like
like how is I was religion added to this
my whole life
like I would not be here today without
God and I'm not ashamed to say it like
um I let me tell you about my living
situation um I live here in Longview now
I was living in a group home out of
rehab you know like I should and I was
miserable I was just I was working two
jobs this was just three months ago
right I was clean but it was I had kind
of started I almost started to cut again
I was like you know um is this all that
is gonna like did I get clean for this
which i think is a feeling that a lot of
people have and I came home and I talked
to my mom about it and she was walking
with a friend from church and the friend
was like we need to call I'm not gonna
mention him but this other lady because
she she can pray over you she's going to
school like to learn more about God and
stuff right and just about healing and
things like that and so she comes and
she prays for me a week later she texts
me and says I've been talking to my
husband and we would like you to move in
with us and they live in a huge house
they just built it like last year and
their whole downstairs is meant for like
chillin and there's a bathroom down
there and a little like tiny tiny like
sink in kitchen area almost and a room
and I come in the garage and I stay down
there and I live there for free they
just felt called by God to help me
that's beautiful yeah and like um I
don't feel cravings for alcohol anymore
and I have I don't take any medications
I was on so many medications for mental
health for not craving for first shaking
I shook like crazy I thought it was
gonna be permanent like I cause of
drinking like you get the DTS oh yeah
yeah I shook all the time and I was
afraid it's gonna happen forever and I
don't shake anymore I mean I shake like
and if I'm nervous I might be a little
shaky right now but um you know like I'm
I'm healed like legit
I think I'm healed and
I've gone to the doctor since I've been
back I they told me when I was in the
ICU that I had the insides of the 55
year old who had drank their whole life
my insides are all healed like I don't I
mean things are great I I just feel like
I've been healed like it's been amazing
and I go they had a couple of
requirements at the house right so I
read a book a month that they suggest
which typically is pretty cool like the
first one was great the second one was
kind of rough but the the third one's
pretty cool and would you recommend
either of those three like to any in
just any reader or I would recommend if
epic faith like yeah it's pretty cool
it's like a story and the cool thing
about is the people I live with met the
author and went to the place in the book
with them so it's like it's the person's
a real person like it's a real story
it's awesome and like I think it's been
here around town because Columbia
Heights Assembly had people read it for
a while oh cool yeah well just just as
someone who I you know I'm still very
open about I just love exploring you
know my spiritual path is new to me too
like a year and a half ago two years ago
the whole spiritual thing like I would
just kind of joke about it like I don't
know it just wasn't for me
you know but I just because I didn't
know anything about it but so so I find
myself like I I am enthralled with with
all the religions like I just I like
learning about all of them so I I love
learning about you know I'll read like
if I read that book I would enjoy every
second of I'm sure if it's a good book
I'm able to read these things and not
like oh I don't agree with this or I
disagree with you know I feel like a lot
of our age group gets caught up with
that sort of thing and they don't really
give it a chance a lot of people like
they I feel like they acknowledge that
the universe is good and like they're
being called and things but that they
are kind of placing it on the universe
when like I feel like it's godlike but I
also don't push it on people like you
know I feel like they they'll come to it
you know I've known God my whole life
but I've never been this close to God no
such things yeah like healing that's
like something that you read about but
like my body is healed like I feel like
a different person like I'm able to
speak about these things this just
happened in March like it's December I'm
talking about it like it's just things
are different like I still have problems
but like not like not like that face up
oh yeah and I just feel strong
I feel like I was put through those
things to help people not to sit and
think I don't know I almost kept them
for myself like okay I've been through
all that I deserve to keep it a secret
you know I deserve to just live a better
life but well in telling people you get
nervous it's like it like because you
don't want people to treat you different
or like treat you like you're fragile or
something all the time I thought that's
how I would always hate a lot like I
just talked with Shane about the same
thing about the podcast I just you know
I just wanted my life is return to
normal now and I want to tell you about
it you know but I'm okay
like yeah I'm like I mean but always
checking on people but like really I'm
not a victim for sure you know if
anything like a survivor straight up you
know and um but I'm not part of this
like new believers group I go to the
promised Church in Woodland it's
freaking amazing and they do a lot of
evangelism there and which is pretty new
to me but they're like finding new
people who believe in God all the time
and it's pretty neat I am I technically
I feel like a new believer because I'm
just like coming in to believe you know
coming back I guess but I've never known
God like this I think I should be a part
of it but I go Thursday's and then I go
to church with my family on Sundays and
what do you do is so I haven't been to
church for so long I remember I went
when I was younger
again I even when I was younger I
enjoyed learning about it I didn't know
what I'd what I knew but yeah so if
anybody you know it's Church a place
that you can kind of like if you felt
like going in the back and you want it
to walk in or like it's like if you're
if you're a struggling and you want to
like I don't know maybe I should learn
learn a little bit about religion or
what what is Christian about like what
what is it I was like to describe that
little step from nothing to like if you
see me it's really weird when you think
that like a family yeah like you think
like me especially I haven't been
treated like a human in a long time like
you know I've been treated fragile I've
been treated like a slave I've been
treated like a drug addict yeah you know
a way of means for someone else right
I've never like I mean since high school
right like or being younger I haven't
been treated like like a person and so I
walked in and I feel like a person again
like they didn't treat me like a fragile
person they saw who I was right then and
they liked it and like now since then
I've told them all kinds of things but I
don't like they haven't changed the way
they look at me at all and they don't
judge
they want to hear about your problems
they want to help you they want to pray
for you like oh they're so inviting and
like the Holy Spirit like I can feel
them around like when we go to places
like that and like they always have
Christmas lights in my lake house but it
makes it like feel like it's like just
straight-up glowing like it's a good
place I love that I mean you you can
feel that I went to
we were just Shaylee and I were just in
London and we went to the I might be
missing a word that's in it but the st.
Peter's Church it's a it's just the
prettiest thing ever like in again the
spirituality is new for me and I'm I'm
so incredibly open to like all these new
experiences that I'm just like what does
it feel like to be in here and the
feeling in that building is just like I
don't I can't put there's not words for
it but there is something that's that's
here you know I mean right certainly and
so you know I I think that that is open
for anybody you know like it's it's
something that you deserve to feel like
you know and that's something that if
you're like what's what's life all about
there's no meaning and you're in this
like terrible downpour it's like you
know look into that there might be
something there that will be a little
bit of a spark
oh yeah seriously and like not only that
things are happening like around the
world right now
like really good things and I mean bad
things too but like there's a lot of
healing happening like like my mom had a
hurt back her backs healed like yeah
like there's there's a place called The
Healing Room in California and like
amazing healing happens like this lady
was driving and on the way she got
healed like she didn't got there yet
and then I Fritton pretty sure it was
there there was a little agenda baby
like that this lady walked there and it
died on the way and she still brought it
there and it came back to life like I'm
not I'm this is gonna freak yeah I know
you know I've been learning about a lot
of stuff like this this lately - I'm not
afraid to like check into it like I mean
miracles man I mean they gotta have some
sort of sort of sort of basis like yeah
like I just feel like I don't know I
feel like it needs to be talked about
like I think it's cool and I think it's
great to explore to you know like like a
lot of times we see stuff or we see
stuff or we hear about it and we're like
it's so weird and so different that I
feel like people gonna make funny if I
talk about it or feel like we're so
weirded out by we can't but it's like
we gotta talk about it you know these
are people are their lifes are getting
better like you that's something we
should explore right yeah like if it's
not for you I guess that's okay but hey
I don't think there's any harm in trying
it like worst case scenario you get
greeted by a lot of friendly people you
know what I mean I think if anything it
matters what church you walk into
because someone overcome strange but I
highly recommend to the promise Church
they're doing some crazy things there
right now it's pretty neat and um and
like even the pastor talks about
addiction like he was addicted to
pornography like straight up and he'll
tell you that and he'll tell you how
he's doing better now and like their
people to human yeah they're all human
it's just a place to go and be a human
you know be thankful for what you got
and I think that's the coolest part
about that new believers group it starts
out and they talk about um they give
thanks for anything that happened in the
last seven days and I always have
something cool to share like it's not
funny here and I never think like oh
seven days like oh that's not a long
time but like it was it can be as simple
as like I went to my little sister's
birthday party for the first time in
like three four years sober this last
weekend oh yeah osode oh that's great
yeah and I just got to be a part of it
and I like said I mean she's a nine now
so she she can say think she'll she'll
say to me I like you so much better now
that you're not drinking and I'll be
like oh my heart wake but she I said to
my stepdad like I just loved being there
he said you were such a big help it was
so nice and I said I was just so nice to
be there like I would have done anything
to be there like and Rory goes I liked
that you were there too and I was just
like ah this is why I live right now
like yeah that's so great I mean in
knowing that you deserve to feel those
feelings cause like I mean there's so
many times where you you would have
never even dreamt that that would happen
but there was also probably even times
where you would have blocked those four
things are happening I know that me like
you know it's it's obviously different
with your traumas but it's you you think
that you deserve to feel these things
but it's like you could trace it back
from Mike way back young like alright I
started feeling that I needed to I
deserve to feel these bad things way
back this far
so the initial just jumping back the
initial you talked about what happen you
order fifty
I think that that admitting that and
talking about that I think that there is
a lot of a lot of people who are living
with these things still inside them you
know like we see like I'm not talking
about like like pop culture and the
media and all that stuff like people you
know whatever but like I think there's a
lot of people who have things that have
happened to them when they were younger
whether they're like what happened to
you or not but I think that speaking of
them and admitting that it did happen in
talking with someone you love about it
or talking with someone who will listen
like going to you know there's plenty of
religious communities there's plenty of
spiritual communities there's plenty of
rehabs too and admitting these things I
feel like just from my experience from
talking to two other people who opened
up to me just as a friend
yeah when those words fall out of their
mouth like I you know I I was really I
was 15 or these things like I mean just
them saying that to someone is is it's
so powerful right in the amount of
healing III think like that moment
they're like when that when it happens
like the you know because I felt healing
that I've even that come to terms with
things that like with myself not even to
another person but that healing that's
definitely a spiritual thing to like
that that melting away the chiseling
away of like oh I'm not holding on to
that thing by myself anymore so I think
that that's pretty powerful um we are
getting up here in time so we're what
we'll do another another five minutes
we'll just wrap it up so Jordan
seriously thank you again like for for
being brave enough to like hit me up to
come here to continue just to like tell
me all your story like I I'm thankful
that you're alive I'm thankful that
you're here sincerely and I'm thankful
that you're going to you know I'm sure
the the next few years for you are gonna
be you're probably gonna help help quite
a few people just by being honest in
yourself so I'm excited to see what
happens do you have any anything you
want to leave any listeners with yeah I
don't know I'm just like thankful to be
talking about it you know um I think
it's important I think that this is
gonna hit home with more people than I
then people really think like because
it's probably if with people in rehab
it's like
percent like but you know there's also
people who had never lived that kind of
life but like rape is something that
happens all the time and like for my
particular situation it wasn't a group
of high school kids that like you were
really well-known in our high schools
like a bunch of seniors and it was like
a bet like who could do it first and I
just happened to be alone with the wrong
one at the wrong time and I never said
anything you know I won't ever say his
name or whatever but um and that's fine
if you do want to report it do it you
know what I mean but I chose not to at
the time and that's your decision right
that was your life you get to yeah and
so um but it's just like I wish that
high school boys knew that they weren't
just messing around you know it's not a
bit like that's like a really important
thing for girls like and boys like
that's just important and to make that
somebody's first experience is really
just not okay yeah and so I just hope
that people kind of like listen and just
know that people have feelings and then
like even as common is like or even when
we were talking about like um maybe and
at work like having somebody be mad
about something I think it's important
to get people thinking like you never
know where the person's been that you're
talking to so like make sure that you
would just talk to them how you would
talk to you would want somebody to talk
to you you know it's really it costs
nothing to be decent to people like
we're all people and so and it makes I
mean it's it's just better walking
around when you just have every single
person that walks by you instead of just
seeing them as like some quick object
it's like it's a person and they were a
child once yeah and they had they you
know their their virginity experience
was different than mine I just just
remembering all these things like this
is a whole person with their whole
intricate life if you can just like
reinsert those yeah get off your phone
and say hi to the people around you that
definitely is a thing well Jordan again
I appreciate you and any listeners out
here who is whose if you're at any stage
in your life and your before the healing
process if you're on the healing process
just know that that you deserve to be on
the healing process you deserve to be on
that path and and you know you might you
might you might be in the cave now but
but like look at Jordan you know
I mean it's still hard so like don't
know no doubt ya know yeah you're
perfect everything's healed but but
that's I'm saying is being on this path
and being open about being on this path
is I mean we could just having these
conversations even having them to where
it's like okay you know I'm gonna have
it if you're a mother right now and
you're like I have a teenage boy like I
wonder if I have to have that
conversation with them like maybe you do
I don't know
right so College about it wouldn't be
hard it wouldn't be it wouldn't hurt
anyone you know certainly yeah I just
think it's very interesting the way
because they're having I mean everybody
seven sex younger anyway but it's just
like a really tough situation we can't
act like it's not there that's for
certain
it's it you know these these are hard
conversations to have important I mean
like where it could go I mean this is a
really exaggerated horrible experience
but yeah okay I just think it's more
common than people think like you just
end up where you end up and um I think
you don't have to accept that like you
can just grow thank things can get
better like you deserve better
absolutely all right well be brave
everybody have a good rest your day junk
out love punk ass
you